what motivates a Russian to work for
что мотивирует россиянина работать за
800 dollars architect how much did you
800 долларов архитектора сколько вы
study
учились
colleague 800 dollars 800 dollars
коллега 800 долларов 800 долларов
multiply by Well what is the rate now
умножить на Ну сколько сейчас уже курс
107 to 100 business 800 to Well let's go to 100
107 на 100 деле 800 на Ну давайте на 100
Yes 800 Uno to 100 80,000 what to multiply here
Да 800 Уно на 100 80.000 что тут множить
80,000 Yes 800 dollars stop stop You You
80.000 Да 800 долла стоп стоп Вы Вы
exactly an architect what are you if you
точно архитектор что вы если множителя
take the Thor multiplier
Тор берёте
Hello Hello where are you
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
from Russia Yes I can see from your face that
откуда России Да я по лицу вижу что
Russia is a city
Россия город
Krasnodar I understood And what do you have here a
какой Краснодар понял А что тут у вас
closet
шкаф
and often do you go to the closet to
а часто вы подходите к шкафу чтобы
look at
посмотреть
the manuals Well yes every day that is
методички Ну да каждый день то есть
when you have some-  then a case in life
когда у вас какая-то случай в жизни
turns out you approach the methodology for
получается вы подходите к методичке на
this case of life choose
этот случай жизни выбираете
it Yes it happens
её Да бывает такое
refresh the closet it seems years or
освежают шкаф он походу годов или
pka were much better than now in
пка были гораздо лучше чем сейчас
fact it will stand for many years I don't
действи он ещё простоит много лет не
want to change this closet wonderful closet
хочу менять этот шкаф замечательный шкаф
cool Soviet according to
прикольно Советский по
GOST I look at  you still have linoleum on the floor
ГОСТу я смотрю у вас линолиум на полу
torn Yes, the linoleum is also excellent,
ещё оборванный Да линолиум отличный тоже
where near the closet there is a hole, everything
где возле шкафа там аж дырка раньше всё
used to be done better than now You know, yes, it
делали лучше чем сейчас Вы знаете да
is better, but there is a hole, there is a hole in the linoleum, there is
лучше но дырка дырка на линолеуме есть
a hole, there is a
возле шкафа есть я вижу дырка Ну вот воз
shadow, there is a shadow, there is a door, no, not
ш тень падает тень падает двер Нет не
near the closet, there is a drawing, but there is  the spot is
возле шкафа есть рисунок А есть пятно
gray This gray spot is
серое Вот это серое пятно - это
torn
сорванный
linoleum this is a
линолеум это
shadow Show Well move this is not a shadow if
тень Покажи Ну ато дви это не тень если
I close the door tightly the shadow will disappear
я плотно закрою дверь то тень исчезнет
So it's not that under the cabinet this is a
Так это не то что под шкафом это тень
black shadow and 10 centimeters in front of the cabinet this
чёрная а сантиметров 10 перед шкафом вот
is a monochromatic
такое однотонное
this is the carpet lying on the  lino Show me that
это ковёр лежит на на лино Покажи что
this is a carpet carpet on lino I don't believe it
это ковёр ковёр на лино это не верю
carpet is lying on show me this is real this is
ковёр лежит на покажи это реально это
a hole from a noma it can't be that a carpet on
дырка от нома не может быть чтоб ков на
lino See I pulled it a little towards
лино Видишь я его потянул немножко на
myself Here's
себя
how you can pull how You can
Вот как ты можешь потянуть как Ты може
pull EU
потянуть ЕС нам
sit for us How are you You  stood up Well, how did you
сиди Как ты Ты привстал Ну как ты
stand up and you're on the carpet how did you
привстал и ты на ковре как ты его
you will pull You will not deceive
потянешь Ты не обману
me I got off the carpet so as not to
меня я пристал с ковра так чтобы не
sit on it and pulled a little and
сидеть на нём и потянул чуть-чуть а а
the chair where I
стульчик куда
reached I put it closer to the
потянулся я его от ближе подставил к
table so that it is not Okay look
столу чтобы он нет Хорошо смотри
maybe I just don't take that
возможно я просто не возьми вот там тот
tip that is at the end of the carpet
кончик что в конце ковёр возле шкафа
lift it up near the closet so I can see that there
приподними чтобы я увидел что там
really is a
действительно это
carpet there and not a hole you don't believe me yes I don't
ковёр а не дырка ты мне не веришь да не
believe No I see a hole
верю Нет я вижу дырку
just look well just for you just
просто хорошо смотри вот чисто для тебя
for you come on you see really a
чисто для тебя
carpet yes yes I understand
Видишь реально ковёр да да всё понял
you see tightly closed the door you see everything
видишь плотно закрыл дверь видишь всё
Magic  I understand the carpet it just blends
Magic понял ковёр он просто сливается
in somehow and your pants are some kind of
как-то с этим а штаны у тебя какие-то
Adidas or something what kind of pants
Adidas или что что это за штаны у тебя
did you have and
были а
pants By the way yes good pants also have such
штаны Кстати да хорошие штаны тоже такие
things They make T-shirts pants are made very quickly the
вещи Делают майки штаны делают быстро
fabric tears thin fabric I've
очень ткань рвётся тонкая ткань эти
been wearing these pants for a while  I don't know how many years I don't
штаны ношу уже не знаю сколько лет я не
remember when I bought them last time well
помню когда я их купил последний раз то
these pants were like in the nineties Yes they
ну эти штаны ещё типа в девяностых Да
weren't in the nineties And in what Well in the
были не не в девяностых А в каком Ну в
noughties  there were
нулевых были
pants really Yes I don't remember the curtains I
штаны действительно Да шторы не помню я
didn't even buy curtains well and I'm still
шторы не покупал даже ну а окна ещё
looking at the windows wooden windows not
смотрю деревянные окна не
metal plastic wooden windows Yes
металлопластик окна деревянные Да
wooden at the bottom there's a handle like that
деревянный бы внизу вон ручка такая ещё
Soviet good wooden windows yes
Советская хорошие окна деревянные да А
Can you really move this
можете тю отодвинуть я реально вот эту
handle or did I imagine it
ручку или это мне не померещилось
look wooden By the way good windows Yes
смотре деревянные Кстати хорошие окна Да
really really this is damn me bau
реально реально вот это блин меня бау
game and
игра и
broke in childhood Yes broke the handle
отломал в детстве Да отломал ручку
Well it's metal you won't break it it
Да ну она металлическая е сломаешь она
twisted out plastic you'll
вывернулась пластиковую ты быстрее
break faster than metal no you didn't
сломаешь чем металлическую не вы не
understand it twisted out with a piece of wood
поняли она с куском дерева
yes
вывернулась да
Yes bad handle
Да плохая ручка
was cool
была прикольно
and you don't have children at home
а у вас детей дома
no because it's scary like
нету нет потому что страшно так типа
holding such Soviet handles down below they
держать такие советские ручки внизу они
can
могут
open but in essence you wanted to talk about something
открыть а по существу Вы хотели о чём-то
I'll just explain Yes in
поговорить Я просто я объясню Да по
essence I just live I
существу Я просто я живу у меня много
have a lot I'll explain why I need this  interesting
есть я объясню почему мне это интересно
I live in Belgium yes I am originally from
Я живу в Бельгии да Я само родом из
Russia but I live in Belgium I
России но живу в Бельгии я дизайнером
work as an interior designer I have 18 years of practice
интерьера работаю у меня 18 лет практики
in 2 years I will be 20 I am
через 2 года будет двадцатому мне
interested I haven't been in for a long time  I'm
интересно я давно не был в России мне
interested in Russia, well, flashbacks, like
интересно вот это ну флешбеки как потому
because now in Europe, uh, they often
что у нас сейчас в Европе э-э часто
order there, for example, in restaurants and
заказывают там например в рестораны и
everything Retro sl Retro style That's exactly in the
всё Ретро сль Ретро стиль Вот именно в
European style of the eighties,
Европейском стиле восьмидесятых
seventies, also in the Soviet style, there are,
семидесятых также в Советском стиле есть
we made for, uh, relaxation edgings they  we
вот мы делали для ээ рела кантов они
made the Katyusha restaurant. We did it in the
делали ресторан Катюша Вот и мы делали в
Soviet style too. That's why I'm
Советском стиле тоже Поэтому мне
interested from a professional point of
интересно с профессиональной точки
view.
зрения
Well, from a professional point of view, we
м ну с профессиональной точки зрения
need to study modern materials. I
надо изучать современные материалы Я
think
думаю
Neva's commercial linoleum is new. No, the
Невы коммерческий линолиум новый нет
point is not in the materials. The point is in the
суть суть не в материалах Суть в
design in the style. Yeah, what new,
оформлении в стилистике Угу Какие новые
well, modern ones.  trends in interior design
ну современные тенденции в интерьере
you can name very different
можете м назвать оче очень разные
look there is minimalism so
смотрите есть э минимализм так вот
now Valiev in Europe we have at
сейчас Валиев в Европе у нас по крайней
least minimalism so all these
мере минимализм так вот эти все там
lofts and so on Yes I am there Loft
лофты и так дальше Да я там Лофт
And so on There is also a house there is
И так дальше Вот есть также хате есть
Coco we have it like that  we call it baroque
Коко мы его так называем Да это барокко
maybe you know when everything is in gold yes
может знаете когда всё в золоте таком да
baroque is called yes when everything there is
барокко называется Да когда всё там
gilded rela edgings really like to indulge in this way
позолоченной рела канты очень любят так
And what do you
баловаться А вы кем
do as an
работаете
architect architect
архитектором архитектор
[music]
[музыка]
what buildings
чего зданий
can you show a model of some building
можете показать макет какого-то здания
that you made no model there is no
который вы делали не макета тут нету
cavity now no one makes models
полости сейчас макеты никто не делает
now everything is modeled in 3D Well then a model Well
сейчас всё моделируют в 3D Ну то макет
printed I
Да ну распечатанный имею в
mean printed no no no no
виду распечатанный не не не нет
photograph No well a photograph of an object
фотография Нет ну фотография объекта
that
который
handed over m photograph of the object I as I
сданный м фотография объекта я как я так
understand it what is on the cabinet is your GOSTs
понимаю то что на шкафу это у вас ГОСТы
yes yes some something like that yes
да да какие-то что-то типа того да
Now it is clear yes because reference books
Теперь понятно да потому что справочники
must be available
надо иметь
under there is such a statement filling
под есть вот такая ведомость заполнение
doorways you will not be able to see from your
проёмов вам не будет видно с
phone  well it does
телефона ну это
n't matter And what makes an interior
неважно А что делает интерьер
modern are you in the Russian classification
современным вы в русской классификации
or in the
или в
normal modern classification
нормаль современ классификаци
modern interior Yes, more precisely,
современный интерьер Да точнее так
the interior is made modern by the modern
интерьер делает современным современный
resident of this interior That's because you
житель этого интерьера Вот потому что
can make a modern interior in the tra
можно сделать современный интерьер в тра
style
стиле
but it will be adapted to modern
но он будет адаптирован под современные
realities it should have  was Yuza Bel yes
реалии у него он должен был Юза Бель да
that is First it should be comfortable that
то есть Первое он должен быть удобный то
is the functionality of this interior so it
есть функционал этого интерьера так он
should not only be beautiful but
должен быть не только красивый а в
first of all comfortable and we should
первую очередь удобный и мы должны
proceed Well that's at least how we
исходить Ну вот по крайней мере как мы
design yes Based on this I don't know
проектируем да Исходя из этого не знаю
how if you look at it  in Russia and in  In the
как вот если смотреть в России да и в
Soviet Union, these door handles are also at
Советском Союзе вот также эти ручки
the bottom. Yes, this is a very scary thing
дверные внизу Да это очень страшная вещь
because a child can
потому что ребёнок может
open it. A small child can open it
открыть маленький ребёнок может открыть
at the bottom. Yes, all this is already kind of out of the question,
внизу Да всё это уже типа отпадает так
just like in our Soviet apartments, for example, the
же как у нас например в советских этих
doors. Yes, Ivan's toilet, how did it
квартирах двери Да туалет Ивана как
open? What do you open and not  you can
открывались е что открываешь и не можешь
go to the
зайти в
toilet Yeah Well children they can generally
туалет Угу Ну дети они могут вообще в
fall out of the window jump out there a lot of
окно выпасть выпрыгнуть там много чего
bad things to do right Yes but for this
плохого делать правильно Да но для этого
look interior elements are made so
смотри элементы интерьера делаются так
that they are as
чтобы они были максимально у
safe as possible of course yes definitely So this
безопасны конечно да обязательно Так что
is a complex big
это сложное большое
direction children are good it costs a lot I
направление деть хороши многого стоит я
know  you have a very difficult job in it you
знаю у вас очень сложная работа в ней
need to know a lot very well about
надо очень много знать очень хорошо
modern trends,
современных тенденциях
styles in
стилях в
materials, understand what is beautiful,
материалах понимать что такое красиво
there is, look, there is, you know, in the World Cup What is the
есть смотрите есть знаете в ЧМ В чём
big problem? The thing is that we have a
большая проблема Дело в том что у нас
multicultural Europe and, for example,
Европа мультикультурная и например
the concept of What is beautiful for me for
понятие Что такое красиво для меня для
you  and for a person, for example, from the Arab
вас и для человека например из арабского
world who lives in Europe, it is completely
мира который живёт в Европе так совсем
different, for example, a
разное например
person who is from Russia or
человек который из России или
from Europe. Yes, a modern
из Европы Да он никогда современный
person will never, for example, put a carpet
человек не будет ложить например ковёр
on the floor because, well, it is bad taste, it is
на пол потому что ну это безвкусица это
some kind of Soviet, yes  a person who is from
какая-то совков да человек который из
Persia, the Middle East, yes, for them, a carpet is
Персии Ближнего Востока да у них ковёр -
an element of national culture, and
это как элемент национальной культуры и
so we had a customer, Akhmet. So, he had a client.
вот у нас был заказчик Ахмет Вот у него
Yes, we designed based on the fact that there
Да мы проектировали исходя из того что
would be carpets on the floor, they immediately told us that there
на полу будут ковры нам сразу говорили
would be carpets on the floor, and
на полу будут
that's it. And  this is also
ковры у вот и всё И от этого тоже
a starting point, yes, for example, if you are
отталкивается да например если ты
doing Europeans, you design one by one, you
делаешь европейцы ты по одному
understand that there will be a
проектирует понимаешь что тут будет
carpet lying here, this is where the
ковёр лежать это начинается
infrastructure begins to grow around the
инфраструктура возрастать вокруг
carpet, you will not be able to do it then
ковра ты уже не сделаешь тогда
it turns out Well, how will this carpet lie
получается Ну а как как ляжет этот ковёр
then yes It turns out how well there is a
тогда да Получается как ну для него
small space left for it then  and
пространство небольшое тогда остаётся и
first we lay down the carpet, that's what's interesting,
мы сначала ложим ковёр вот что интересно
yes, and around the carpet we place the
да а вокруг ковра уже расставляем
functional element so that everything
функциональный элемент по что всё вот
is there, for them the carpet is some kind of
есть вот для них ковёр - это какая-то
sacred thing, they can't live without
сакральная вещь они не могут вот без
this carpet, for them it's an element of
этого ковра для них это элемент
wealth, an element of
богатства элемент там
status, Well, that came  from the past
статуса Ну это пришло ещё из прошлого
when it was considered that a carpet is a sign of a
когда считалось что ковёр - это признак
wealthy person, not in the Soviet
зажиточного человека не это в Советском
Union. And for them, it's not like a
Союзе А у них у них это не то что ков
carpet, carpets were wallpaper in their culture.  there
зажи у них в культуре ковры были обоев
were no yes there for example that is and carpets
не было да там например то есть а ковры
that were
это было
also in the Eastern world There they could they did
и в Восточном мире Там они могли у них
not have tables Yes so the carpet
не было столиков Да вот ковёр
was spread on the ground they laid down sat on the
расстилался на земле ложили садились на
ground and had a meal on the
землю и трапезу проводили на
carpet And do you know 3D modeling
ковре А вы владеете 3D моделированием
No I am not a fashion designer Well that is  I
Нет я не модельер Ну то есть я не
don't do modeling That is, I do I
провожу моделирование То есть я делаю я
distribute tasks to the performer
раздаю задачи исполнителя
specific yes that is, I
конкретных да то есть я веду вместе с
communicate with clients together with our boss Yes I
нашим шефом общение с клиентам Да я
do the tasks of the post we also have someone
делаю задачи поста у нас есть ещё тот
who is responsible for 3D modeling Yes he already
кто отвечает за 3D моделинг Да он уже
sets the technical task for the performers according to the models  Yes, I do
ставит по моделям Да я делаю
conceptual tasks like that, that is,
концептуальные задания так то есть
for example, what should be, yes, what should
например что должно быть да Какие должны
be the placement, what are the key things, yes, for
быть размещение Какие ключевые вещи Да
example, they prescribe the terms of reference, yes,
вот например ээ прописывают тза Да что
what is the carpet, we have this one, it should
вот ковёр У нас вот этот он должен
lie, it should lie, the central
лежать он должен лежать Центральный
element of the hall, the living room, if they are making
элемент зала гостиная если делают
a living room, yes, the central element  - this is an
гостиную Да Центральный элемент - это
oval ellipse carpet That is, uh,
овалов эллипсом ковёр Вот то есть ээ
and some carpets exist We are just a
причём некоторые ковры есть Мы прям вот
person saying that this will be We are
человек говорит что вот он будет Мы
measuring this carpet really so that
замеряем этот ковёр действительно чтобы
we we knew the parameters Yes I
мы мы знали параметры Да я тех задания
also set technical assignments uh there is a person who
также ставлю ээ есть человек который
sets the technical assignment of the 3D model to
ставит уже техническое задание 3D моделя
those who make the 3D model How is it
тем кто делает 3D модель Как это
in Russian not a model how is it in Russian I
по-русски не моделя как это по-русски я
don't know
не знаю
modeler modeler Yes we have a mode simply
моделлер моделлер Да у нас моде просто
in Russian  about the visa visualizer here is a
по-русски о визу визуализатор вот
visualizer simply no yes in the Russian
визуализатор просто нету да в русском
language such a correspondence Here And by
языке такого соответствия Вот А у Вас
the way did you order an interior design
кстати Вы заказывали дизайн интерьера
Or is it just that way for you well it
Или это у вас так ну ситуативно
turned out to be situational we didn't order anything as if
получился ничего не заказывали как бы
we simply didn't strive here to
просто как мы не стремились тут особо
make ourselves a stylish interior
интерьер какой-то сделать себе стильный
simple people were
мы простые были люди
not rich for us The main thing was Well put a
небогатые нам Главное было Ну поставить
wardrobe bed in the sense of not rich If you are an
шкаф кровать в смысле небогатые Если вы
architect You how much do you earn
архитектор Вы сколько вы зарабатываете
as an
как
architect I can now afford to
архитектор я сейчас уже могу позволить
do a good renovation there but I am a
себе там ремонт сделать хороший но я
canned conservative
консерва консервативный
person to go dumb
челове неметь
so it's
так
normal how much salary do you have as an
нормально сколько зарплат у вас как
architect colleague Well I  I don't want to
архитектора коллега Ну я не хочу сейчас
spread now how much I
распространяться сколько у меня там
earn there is normal Well,
заработок нормально Ну
approximately well I don't want to
приблизительно ну не хочу я
spread and declare my
распространяться и декларировать свои
earnings well Okay, what do you have as an
заработки хорошо Ладно какие у вас у
architect in Russia  salary range
архитектора в России вилка зарплат
a
а
from 8000 to
от 8000 до
250 like this, that is, an architect
250 вот так вот такая то есть архитектор
in Russia gets from
в России получает от
800 less than 800 euros to somewhere around 2300 euros
800 меньше 800 евро до где-то 2300 евро
Well, I can't translate it in my head how much the
Ну я так перевести не могу в уме сколько
euro exchange rate is now I don't know I'm Lyakh
там курс евро сейчас я не знаю я вам Лях
SKA I can  look if we divide uh even
СКА я могу смотри е если делим ээ даже
by 100 if we divide yes It comes out from
на 100 если делить да Это получается от
800 to 500 listen here in Belgium Yes
800 до 500 слушайте у нас в Бельгии Да
uh a person who works in
ээ человек который работает в доставке
pizza delivery gets 3,000 euros
пиццы получает 3.000 евро
as Wait you must be joking Well I don't
как Подождите вы наверное шутите Ну я не
believe it can't be that an architect in
верю не может быть чтобы архитектор в
Russia Russia  it seems like the richest country
России Россия же вроде богатейшая страна
oil gas gold diamonds and a bunch of everything is
нефть газ золото алмазы и куча есть всё
being built damn everything is like this damn how does an
строится блин всё такие Блин как это
architect get from 800 dollars to a
получает архитект от 800 долларов до
ceiling of 2500 No I told you here is an
потолок 2500 Нет я вам сказал вот
architect these are vacancies If you
архитектор это вот вакансии Если Вы
look at headhunter there is such a
посмотрите на хедхантере там вот такой
range of salaries from 8000 somewhere-  then there is a salary range of up to
разброс зарплат от 8000 где-то там до
but if  someone is a
вот такой разброс зарплат Но если кто-то
private architect, he works for
частный архитектор он работает сам на
himself, he can earn more, how can he
себя он может получать и больше как он
afford it, how can he
потянет это как
afford it? Stop. We just think that we have
потянет Стоп У нас просто я думаю у нас
help for the unemployed. Yes, 1,700 euros a month,
помощь безработным Да 1700 евро в месяц
that is, it turns out that an unemployed person
то есть получается у нас безработный
in Belgium gets twice as much
получает в Бельгии в два раза больше
as  minimum salary of architects in
чем минимальная получка Архитекторов в
Russia something
России чтото
How much does a utility bill cost How much
Сколько стоит Коммунальный плаж Сколько
does a utility bill cost Utility
стоит Коммунальный плаж Коммунальный
payment you It feels like a third of your
платёж вы Такое ощущение будто треть
salary goes to utility payment
зарплаты на Коммунальный платёж уходит
Utility payment is a small
Коммунальный платёж это маленькая
drop in your salary Well, yes,
капелька в зарплате Ну да
yes, how much
да сколько
T Utility payment you need to look at
Т Коммунальный плаж надо смотреть
How much does a car cost How much does a
Сколько стоит автомобиль Сколько стоит
TV cost utility how much  there he is well you can
теле комунальный сколько там он ну можно
buy a washing machine for example for 20
стиральную машинку купить например за 20
or for 40,000 washing machine I see Well
или за 40.000 стиральную машинку Ясно Ну
look the same washing machine in
смотри одинаковую стиральную машинку в
Belgium it will be cheaper than in
Бельгии она будет дешевле чем в
Russia I don't know the point of comparing this I
России я не знаю смысл это сравнивать Я
think
думаю
that this is a normal normal salary
что это нормальный нормальная зарплата
on which you can live normally and not  We
на которую можно так нормально жить а не
thought, for example, to go and work as an
думали например поехать поработать
architect somewhere in Europe. I
архитектором где-то в Европе
didnt think about why I was here.
не думал почему меня здесь Нормально
Everything is fine somehow, and it seems like we
както всё нормально та вроде бы
earned money. I think.  Listen, if you are a
заработали Я думаю Слушайте если вы
good architect, not
хороший архитектор не
Kato, you can get about 10
Като можно в месяц получать порядка 10я
euros a month, maybe,
евро может быть
yeah, well, you know what the deal is. Yes, that's what
да ну Понимаете в чём дело Да тоже вот
people strive for, more, more, more. But
люди стремятся больше больше больше А
where do they need it? Why, I'm
куда им это Зачем им бо
explaining to them. Look, if you worked for about a
объясняю Смотрите если вы поработали о
year in Europe for a salary of 10,000 euros.  it's the
год в Европе на зарплату 10.000 евро это
same as if you worked in Russia for 10 years
всё равно что вы 10 лет работали в
for 800
России по 800
euros, everyone gets that kind of money there and
евро прям все получают такие деньги там
you Well, if you're a good architect, you
да у вас Ну если вы архитектор хороший
'll get ten in any case,
десятку будете получать по-любому
where does that kind of money come from? You
откуда такие деньги вообще Вот вы
tell me what he
скажите мнен что он что
gets that much money for,
вот столько денег получает за
why?  for what does he get them for his work,
что за что он их получает за свою работу
that is, he can
то есть он может
work for a month and then
получается поработать месяц и потом
completely forget about everything and not work, yes,
вообще на всё забить и не работать да
if you live in Russia, who motivates him to
Если жить в Росии кто его мотивирует
work more, then if he
работать больше потом если он столько
can buy so much for himself, I will say because because
может себе купить я скажу потому что
because  man yes he
потому что с потому что человек да он
gets more Yes he can
получает больше Да он может
for CX children ti Yes he can go on
для СХ детей ти Да может поехать
vacation for example somewhere to the Maldives
отдохнуть например куда-то на Мальдивы
ti Well what motivates me other what
ти Ну как что мотивирует меня другое что
motivates a Russian to work for 800
мотивирует россиянина работать за 800
dollars architect how long did you study
долларов архитектора сколько вы учились
colleague  800 dollars 800 dollars
коллега 800 долларов 800 долларов
multiply by Well, what is the rate now
умножить на Ну сколько сейчас уже курс
107 to 100
107 на 100
de 800 Well, let's
де 800 Ну давайте на
[music]
[музыка]
100 0.000 what is there to multiply 80.000 Yes 800
100 0.000 что тут множить 80.000 Да 800
dollars stop stop You You are definitely an
долларов стоп стоп Вы Вы точно
architect what are you if you take the Thor multiplier
архитектор что вы если множитель Тор
And to be sure so as not to make
А чтобы наверняка чтобы не
a mistake I  honestly I've
ошибиться Я честно я честно говоря
never made a mistake in multiplying by
никогда в умении ошибся умножению на
Yeah 800 80,000 - that's an average
Угу 800 80.000 - это такой средний
architect like an average
архитектор как средний
one in 3 years 3 years he can earn
года 3 года 3 года он может зарабатывать
that kind of money stop stop stop stop stop you
такие деньги стоп стоп стоп стоп стоп вы
said from 80 that is now it turns out that
говорили от 80 то есть теперь получается
for an architect to earn 80,000 rubles
чтоб архитектору зарабатывать 80.000 руб
800  dollars he needs to work for 3 years
800 долларов ему нужно 3 года поработать
so there are architects who get even less
так есть архитекторы которые ещё меньше
Yes beginners beginners
получают Да начинающие начинающие
who have just started working just
которые только начали работать только
graduated from the institute how much does such an
окончили институт сколько такой
architect
архитектор
get Well there he can get 40 thousand
получаю Ну там тысяч 40 может получить
Well he studies he doesn't know anything yet he
Ну он учится он ещё не знает ничего он
came He earns
пришёл Он зарабатывает
experience they teach him Well  What can he
стаж его учат он Ну что он может
do? Here.  he worked there for 3 years
делать-то Вот он проработал там 3 года
what can he do A understood that is to say receive All
что он может А понял то есть получа Всё
I understood that is to say receive he comes
я понял то есть его получа он приходит
after university the first year they teach him to
после университета первый год его учат
multiply by 100 so that he can add two zeros
умножать на 100 чтобы он два нуля мог
Yes for example the second year they teach him to
Дописать Да например второй год учат
divide by
делить на
100 they teach him uh a lot of things  work they teach you to
100 его учат ээ много чему работать учат
work there you need to
работать там надо много
know a lot really a
знать по-настоящему
lot I just don't understand why then
много просто я не понимаю зачем тогда
go to work as an architect and get
идти на работу архитектором и получать
400 dollars in the long term so that 800 would
400 долларов в перспективе чтобы 800
be in the long term well
было в перспективе ну
Well why do people
Ну зачем люди вообще
live well And how much does an architect need to
Живут хорошо А сколько нужно архитектору
work so that he gets 2  with
работать чтобы ему он получал уже 2 с
pono Well 2,500
поно Ну 2.500
250,000 probably need to open your own
250.000 надо наверное открывать уже свою
design office and then you will
контору проектную и тогда ты будешь
receive stop
получать стоп
Yeah That is 2500 dollars can
Ага То есть 2500 долларов это может
only be received by the owner of the design
только получать собственник проектной
office and the worker here is a hired architect
конторы а рабочий вот наёмный архитектор
what is his
сколько его потолок
salary ceiling is I can for example go there is
зарплаты есть я могу например пойти есть
such a company where you can earn  such
такая фирма где можно зарабатывать такие
money but they will ask for much
деньги но там спрашивать будут гораздо
more
больше
there it is called difficult to
там не дых нуть называется будет сложно
sew for the Armed Forces Sometimes it is better to receive less
за ВС сшить Иногда лучше меньше получать
but live more calmly
но жить спокойнее
understood by
поняли по
debt What is there what What  you will need to
дол Что там такое что Что нужно будет
work
работать
directly Well, at least that's what they say
пря Ну так рассказывают по крайней мере
there Booth will ask for everything there will be a
там Бут за всё спрашивает будет режим
multitasking mode on you several
многозадачности на вас навет несколько
objects you will need to
объектов вам надо будет несколько
simultaneously keep several objects in memory
объектов одновременно вести в памяти
keep many different moments on
держать много всяких моментов по
several
нескольким
objects answer all sorts of questions
объектам отвечать на всякие вопросы
Builders who will call you
Строителей которые будут вам звонить
ask about the situation
спрашивать положе
in general you will have to stay late to
в общем надо будет оставаться до поздна
work that is Stop That is not
работать то есть это Стоп То есть это не
for an eight-hour work day 2500
за восьмичасовой рабочий день 2500 да
yes it turns out well of course you can achieve that they
получается ну можно конечно же добиться
don't bother you to
того чтобы на вас не напрягались
work there is Tae Well okay here's how much
жать есть Тае Ну хорошо вот сколько
does that architect earn who
зарабатывает тот архитектор который вот
works here 8  no
работает вот 8 часов не
more hours well as I told you it
больше ну как я вам говорил он вполне
can be from 80 to
может от 80 до
250 not 250 We understood that in order to
250 не 250 Мы же поняли что чтобы
get 250 you need to, in short, have
получать 250 нужно короче чтобы тебя на
them drive you until the night there
те ездили аж до ночи
is a pile-up yes there is a pile-
бывает завал да бывает
up and of course you understand it is better to
завал и конечно сам понимаешь лучше
stay and finish something  so that later you
остаться и что-то доделать чтобы потом
don't have to remember the next day what
не не вспоминать на следующий день что
you forgot to do yesterday It happens that
ты там забыл сделать вчера Бывает такое
everyone stays late at work it's
все задерживаются на работе это
normal damn it's kind of strange I
нормально блин как-то странно я что-то
don't understand something I was just looking And what
не по Я просто смотрел А вы в каком
city do you live in  in Krasnodar in
городе живёте вкраснодаре в
Krasnodar he gets I didn't work for them I don't
Краснодаре получает я им не работал я не
know how much but now I'm looking I'm
знаю сколько ну сейчас посмотр мне
just interested They say he
просто интересно Говорят он примерно
gets about the same there he can
также и получает там 100000 может
get 100,000 a month And then 150
получить в месяц А то 150
even couriers now
даже курьеры сейчас
they get very well Yes, a courier
они очень хорошо получают Да курьер
in Krasnodar those are from 7,000 to 200,000 br
Краснодара те вот от 7000 до 200000 брь
Well, why is he degrading? He rides
Да ну а что он деградирует он ездит на
this bike. He doesn't
этом велосипеде он не
develop. There's snow and rain and ice. You
развивается и снег и дождь и гололёд Ты
have to go. I saw how one courier
должен ехать Я видел как одного курьера
was hit by a
сбили на
car. This isn't such a simple job either.
машине Это тоже не такая Простая Работа
In fact, well,
на самом деле
how can you multiply it by the table? Well,
Ну как на стол умножить например ну да
what's the big deal?  with these pedals can only
чему там с этими педалями может только
Yes, damn, this is of course brutal Well, you just
Да блин это жесть конечно Ну просто вы
surprised me That is, in Belgium, an
меня удивили То есть у нас в Бельгии
architect is one of the paid
архитектор - это одна из оплачиваемых
professions architects doctors
профессий архитекторы доктора
lawyers damn Ah, how can an architect
юристы блин Ахи как архитектор может
earn damn 400 dollars They
получать блин 400 долларов Украину
show Ukraine Why do you have it And why Ukraine
показывают Почему у вас А почему Укра
Why Ukraine  shows [ __ ] gift from
Почему Украину показы сри подарок из
Ukraine my friends sent because I'm
Украины мои друзья скинули потому что я
here in Belgium I'm with morom from Rostov Yes I'm
тут в Бельгии я с мором из Ростова Да я
in Belgium when  my own began I accepted
в Бельгии когда начался свой я принимал
refugees from Ukraine They lived with me they have
беженцев из Украины Они у меня жили они
already returned to Ukraine they sent me
уже вернулись в Украину они мне выслали
this hoodie Yes and I put Ukraine
вот эту такую худи Да а ставил Украину
Because I am interested in communicating with
Потому что мне интересно общаться с
Ukrainians I asked them how do you
украинцами я их спрашивал как вы
feel about me, a Russian who
относитесь ко мне россиянину который
has been living in Europe for 18 years  in 2 years
живёт в Европе уже 18 лет через 2 года
[music]
[музыка]
Well, how can it be
Ну и как
treated
относится
ambiguously ambiguously Well, I am still a citizen of the
двояко двояко Да ну я всё-таки гражданин
Russian Federation, they immediately say to me
Российской Федерации меня сразу говорят
You are a citizen I say
Ты гражданин Я говорю
Well, it's my fault too, yes, there is some of it
Да ну как бы моя вина тоже да в этом
I understand that I am helping the ZSU I am
есть я понимаю что я помогаю зсу Я
sending part of my salary  to help the
отправляю часть своей зарплаты на помощь
armed forces of Ukraine by the way
вооружённым силам Украины меня кстати
one
одно
of me from Rostov Sanya Prokhorov we would
из Ростова Саня Прохоров бы мы с ним за
sit at the same desk with him it turned out
одной партой сидели так получилось
a little unpleasant
немножко неприятно
In short we helped the Kraken unit
Короче мы помогали подразделению кракин
we here in Belgium organized training camps for the
мы тут в Бельгии организовали сборы для
Kraken unit this is Nako in the
подразделения Кракен это Нако в
Kharkov region they were special forces
Харьковской области они были р спецназ
we gave them drones  in short, they
мы им дроны короче
passed on to them Degi Naro
пере им передавали Деги Наро
zali My classmate Sanya Prokov Da
зали Мой одноклассник Саня проков Да
died right there near Kupyansk in
погиб как раз там под купянском в
Kharkov we were sitting at a desk with him and
Харькове мы с ним за партой сидели и
in short,
короче
uh, I'm showing us these
ээ показываю нам скидывают вот эти
Krakens are sending us videos of their
Кракен скидывают видео ээ своих
work and we have a Odnoklassniki chat on Telegram
отработок и у нас телеграме есть чат
because after the
Одноклассников потому что после встречи
classmates' meeting there was one and they were sending us that Sanya
одноклассников был и скидывали что Саня
Prokhorov died and he was killed by a drone and they
Прохоров погиб да э дроном убила и
are also showing a video. Yes, he says that the
показывают тоже видео Да вот говорит что
Ukrainians are chasing this video.
украинцы гоняют вот этот видео
in this video Sanya Prokhorov and this is the
то на этом видео Саня Прохоров и вот это
video that they send us That is, it
то видео которое нам скидывают То есть
turns out I'm just saying fate, you
получается я вот просто говорю судьба
know That's something we are In short, we
понимаешь Вот это что-то есть мы Короче
were sitting at a desk Yes, when he started his
сидели за партой Да он когда начали сво
he went He signed a contract and I helped
он пошёл Подписал контракт а я помогал
Ukrainian refugees here in Belgium  and
украинским беженцам тут в Бельгии и
transferred money to the ZSU And he also wrote to him
передавал деньги на зсу Да ещё ему писал
why do you need this Contra he is not you are NATO
зачем тебе этот Контра он нет вы НАТО
There and so on And so it turns out my
Там и так дальше Да и получается мой
Drone yes
Дрон да
my Drone to which I donated and killed
мой Дрон на который я донатил да грохнул
Sanya Prokhorov there was a video in short there was
Саню Прохорова там видео короче было
such a thing he runs this operator children at the
такое он бежит этот оператор дет за
desk we  we sat at the desk with him for 11 years,
партой мы сидели с ним 11 лет за партой
just from the first grade, that's how they
просто с первого класса вот нас как
sat us down for the first bell. Yes, we
посадили на первый звонок Да мы на
were sitting at the third desk  third desk right
третьей парти сидели третья парта Правый
row That's how it was until now desks were changing I
ряд Вот так и до си только менялись
move us so that we would
парты нас пересаживаю чтобы мы это ну
n't have this squinting, now from there, now from there
косоглазия не было то оттуда то оттуда
But we sat like that yes we sat he
Но мы вот так и сидели да мы сидели он с
was from the neighboring house oh and in short the video is
соседнего дома был о и короче видео
flying Drone Sanya is running Sanya is running from  him
летит Дрон Саня бежит Саня бежит от него
Yes there on the video Well the face is not very visible
Да там на видео Ну лицо Не сильно видно
but who knows maybe he can be recognized
так но э кто его знает может распознать
Yes he runs away from the street No no
Да он убегает ули Да нет по походке не
you can't recognize him by his gait not by his gait he turns around
по походке не узнаешь он разворачивается
sometimes Well when Drone there is a good camera
иногда Ну когда Дрон там камера хорошая
these Ukrainians have and he runs away runs
у этих у украинцев и он убегает убегает
away in short  The drone hits him
убегает короче Дрон ему попадает ээ в
right in the face, yes, I dont know how these
вот просто вниц да я не знаю как эти
power steering operators that we and they are so
операторы ГУР на которые мы с они вот
filigree, they even
просто филигранные они даже в танк в
put this one in the open hatch of a tank, in short, and Well, I dont
открытый люк садили этот короче и Ну не
want to describe what was there, yes,
хочу описывать что там было да Короче
in short, there was one Sanya, there were several
короче был один Сань стало несколько
San and I understand I have very
Сань и как бы и я понимаю у меня очень
mixed feelings Yes I don't know this is
двоякие чувства Да вот я не знаю это
some kind of damn Movie you can make right
блин какой-то Фильм можно снять прямо
here no one will even believe Yes a
вот никто не поверит даже Да друг
childhood friend sat  we were friends together there we fought
детства сидели дружили вместе там бились
together there we fought against the boys from
вместе там бились против пацанов из
another school in short for Lenka Nikifor we
другой школы короче за Ленкой никифора
fell out together Yes, all sorts of things happened I went
выпадали вместе Да всякое было я поехал
to Europe
в Европу
he NATO America started his own he
он НАТО Америка началось сво он
went he went himself not that In short, they
пошёл пошёл сам не то что Короче это его
took him Moby he went for the Motherland himself everything yes
взяли Моби он сам пошёл за Родину всё да
and  I helped with the guys We
а я помогал вместе с ребятами У нас тут
have an organization here
есть организация
Russians are washing against the war we collect
мытся россияне против войны мы собираем
money and send it to the
э деньги и отправляем на вот
Krakin unit from the GUR and they
подразделение кракин от ГУР и нам
send it to us We have a chat they
присылают У нас есть чатик они нам
send us videos and really now I'm
скидывают видосы и реально я сейчас
just watching Yes at first I
просто смотрю Да у меня сначала у меня
had  it feels like, well, damn, it
было такое ощущение что как бы ну блин
feels like I'm helping to fight the
вроде как бы я помогаю бороться с
occupiers Yes, but it feels like, well, you see,
оккупантами Да но вроде как бы ну видите
life has put you on different
как жизнь расставила вас по разные
sides,
стороны
you're on the
вы он с
other side, no, no, I'm not, no, no, no, no, that's
другой нет нет не я нет нет нет нет нет
wrong. It's wrong. I defended
неправильно Неправильно я я защитил
the Ukrainian some-  then a girl or a guy Yes,
украинскую какую-то девушку или парня Да
from the fact that Sanya Prokhorov their That's what I
от того чтобы Саня Прохоров их Вот что я
first also think damn Sanya and then I
сначала тоже думаю блин Саня а потом
think look Sanya Made his choice Sanya
думаю смотри Саня Сделал свой выбор Саня
stood on the side of evil nya became on  side he
встал на сторону зла ня стал на сторо он
went to Ukraine to kill people from drive
пошёл в Украину убивать людей из сгонять
them away from me There lived here in Belgium a family from
их у меня Жила тут в Бельгии семья с
Kharkov from Severnaya Saltovka they
Харькова с Северной салтовки они
showed a video of what happened to their house Yes
показывали видео что с ихними в дом Да
they left evacuated Yes and their house
они уехали эвакуировались Да а ихний дом
once a nine-story building is generally brutal you
раз девятиэтажку та вообще жесть вы себя
calmed your conscience you were able  I don't I do
успокоили свою совесть вы смогли Я не я
n't mean that I donate more I even
не то что в смысле я больше я даже
started
больше начал
donating more Sanya went to kill went to kill
донатить Саня пошл убивать пошёл убивать
yes he yes he I think yes I we had a
да он да он Я считаю да я у нас было
meeting of this community of ours like
собрание вот этой нашей общины типа
Russian against war I told I
русский против войны я рассказывал я
say damn look and we should
говорю блин смотрите и мы должны
donate  more on drones because
донатить больше на дроны потому что
more
больше
Sanya Prokhorov who go to kill people in
Сань Прохоров которые идут убива людей в
Ukraine will not come to Ukraine you understand will not
Украину не придут в Украину понимаете не
come more than Krakin after
придут больше того кракин после того как
Sanya Sanya was smashed in DM at the
Саню Саню ещё в дм это бахнули в
end now when they entered the Kursk region
конце сейчас когда в курскую область
Yes in the Kursk region It seems that it is
зашли Да в курскую область Вроде это ж
there  Russia is all crap
там Россия всё кракин
just brutal I don't know those people who
просто жесть Я не знаю тех людей кто там
meet those drones there Who dies some
встречает эти дроны Да кто умирает какой
other Sanya Prokhorov from some other
другой Саня Прохоров из каких-то других
there I don't  I know where they are coming from Yes
там я не знаю откуда они лезут Да
North Korean Sanya is passing by it doesn't matter Yes but
северокорейский Саня прохо неважно Да но
I understand that my Dron for my Donat
я понимаю что мой Дрон за мой Донат
frees the guy from Rostov from this
парня из Ростова освобождает от этой
Kremlin you understand
кремлёвской понимаешь
yeah I understand I
угу Понимаю
understand it's cool And who are you by
понимаю это классно А вы кто по
nationality Russian Well how is it that
национальности русский Ну как наполовину
my father is half Russian And my mother is a Chuvash from
у меня отец русский А мама чувашка из
Cheboksary  She studied in Rostov and
Чебоксар Она училась в Ростове и
met her father and stayed and Well,
познакомилась с отцом и осталось и Ну
this is the Soviet Union, there was still a letter
это Советский Союз ещ был бук
pronounces Yes, I dont lisp, no,
выговаривает Да я не картавлю нет
tell me 33
скажите 33
bogatyrs, the primer somehow gets lost 33
богатыря буквар как-то теряется 33
bogatyrs No, Im
богатыря Нет меня
normal, dyrs-dyrs Everything is fine with my
норма дыр-дыр Всё нормально у меня с
diction
дикцией
Yes, if youre like  are you hinting that I might be
Да если вы типа намекаете что я может
Jewish No, I'm not Jewish My father is Russian My
еврей Нет не еврей Я папе русский по
mother is Chuvash I can see right away that you are our
мами чуваш я вижу сразу что вы наш
man our r absolutely normal You
человек наш р абсолютно нормально Вы
even by your worldview it's immediately
даже по вашему Вот мировоззрению сразу
clear that you are ours And who are you by
видно что вы наш А вы кто по
nationality You are good You are for
национальности Вы же добро Вы же за
good I am for  good Yes For peace in the whole world
добро Я за добро Да За мир во всём мире
Yes for good donate yes
Да на добро донати да
ruy man because you are for good I  for
руй человек потому что вы за добро Я за
good
добро
Dania For peace in the whole world Yes I am for the fact that
Даня За мир во всём мире Да я за то что
the thing is that we have these
дело в том что вот у нас есть эти
none these just clarify Yes we have
никаких эти просто уточни Да у нас
look we have
смотрите у нас есть
this Belgian politician Mion Korch he
этот бельгийский политик мион корч он
put forward such a thesis that peace is not the
выдвинул такой тезис что мир - это не
absence of war peace  this is the absence of
отсутствие войны мир это отсутствие
Moscow and there is something in this,
Москвы и что-то в этом есть вот
this Kremlin one has captured our
Кремлёвский вот этот захватил нашу
Russia Yes, our people Yes, if his Moscow
Россию Да наш народ Да если его Москву
or at least the Kremlin Yes, then the peoples
или хотя бы Кремль Да Всё тогда народы
will become free From whom From what From the
станут свободными От кого От чего От
Kremlin freedom, you understand What
кремлёвской свобо вы понимаете Какая
mechanism is this society is arranged in such a way that
механизм это общества устроены так что
someone will definitely come to replace him later
кто-то потом приходит на смену
And the question is who will
обязательно И вот вопрос в том кто
come The question is no, a little bit,
прит Вопрос нет немножко нери
it will be like with the Soviet Union Yes, the
это будет как с советским союзом Да
Soviet Union fell apart and it was gone The
Советский Союз развалился и его не стало
same thing should happen with Russia with the
тоже самое должно произойти с Россией с
Russian Federation Yes,
Российской Федерацией Да это
these are our lectures on political science  were Yes
вот у нас лекции по политологии были Да
at the university and there we read, here is Janusz
в университете и там читали вот Януш
Bugajski, a
бугайский такой
very famous specialist on the collapse
да очень известный специалист по развалу
of Russia By the way, the Ukrainians gave me his
России Кстати мне украинцы передали его
book, look, I'm now where is it
книгу смотрите Я сейчас е где вот
Well, it's in Ukrainian I'm already learning Ukrainian
Ну она на украинском Я уже украинский
Yes  it is impossible
Да не спроможна
[music]
[музыка]
state
держава
instruction
инструкция
with shmani of
с шмани
Russia that is instruction ramanii it is
России то есть инструкция рамани это
like in Ukrainian
типа как украински
parts to tear apart Russia
части разорвать Росси
T it is in Ukrainian parts parts Yes to
Т это по-украински части части Да на
tear apart So here I am I am
разорвать Так что вот я это я по ней
trying to
украински пробую
study Ukrainian on it it is a little difficult well somehow
изучать тяжело даётся немножко ну как-то
according to this book you want to tear Russia apart
по этой книжке хотите разорвать Россию
not that I want Yes but I know people
да не то что я хочу Да но я знаю людей
who do this professionally
которые этим профессионально занимаются
Yes and the Armed Forces are doing it to destabilize the
Да и делают ВС для дестабилизации
situation in the Russian Federation so that
ситуации в Российской Федерации чтобы
it collapses the same way the
она развалилась так как развалилась
Russian Empire collapsed as a result of the First
Российская империя в результате первой
World War the same way the Soviet
мировой войны как развалился Советский
Union collapsed as a result  losing the Cold
Союз в результате проигрыша в холодной
War and now the same
войне и сейчас идёт тот же самый
scenario is going on there the Union entered Afghanistan and
сценарий там Союз вошёл в Афганистан и
overextended itself here Russia entered Ukraine and
надорвался тут Россия зашла в Украину и
overextended itself yes look there is a complete n
надорвалась да смотрите идёт полная н
No you understand Well entered Afghanistan
Нет вы понимаете Ну вошёл в Афганистан
Well there were sanctions I agree there were sanctions
Ну были санкции Я согласен были санкции
but Nasr
но у Наср
Mikhail Sergeyevich he  admitted that he
Михаил Сергеевич он признавался что он
himself was leading the activities towards the
сам вёл деятельность в направлении
collapse but now
развала но сейчас у
we have Vova Putin a real street kid
нас Вовка Путин реальный дворовой пацан
who was brought up by the film Kortik he
который воспитан фильмом Кортик он об
himself told about it he has been
этом сам рассказывал он
like that since childhood  wanted to become a spy
такой с детства хотел стать разведчиком
Well, I'm from a spy, he played a spy as
Ну я с разведчика вот в разведчика он в
a child, he liked this game so much,
детство играл ему эта игра так
he still plays it,
понравилась он до сих пор в неё играет
he's not like Mishka, he's not like
он не такой как Мишка он не такой как
Mishka, Mishka is like Zhirinovsky said,
мишка мишка - это как Жириновский сказал
we already had one who avenged his brother
у нас уже был один отомстил за брата Да
And then there was another weirdo he
и потом ещё другой чудак был он за
avenged his grandfather Soviet Union Vova is not like that
отомстил Советский Союз Вовка не такой
you understand how many sanctions were introduced Now
понимаете сколько санкций ввели Сейчас
you Compare how many sanctions there were then
вы Сравните сколько санкций было тогда
how many
сколько
sanctions and compare Who is Mishka and who
санкций и сравните Кто такой Мишка и кто
is Vovka this is va come on come on
такой Вовка это ва давай давай давай
Let's compare look Sorry
Давайте Давайте сравним смотри Извините
Mishka  was full look I will say so
Мишка был полне смотрите я я скажу так
it's all in short lyrics Yes really
это всё короче лирика Да реально
Russia Russia has lost the gas hub to
Россия Россия потеряла газовый хаб в
Europe completely yes Russia has lost all
Европу полностью да Россия потеряла всё
influence in Syria and in Africa in the Middle
влияние в Сирии и в Африке на Ближнем
East the Soviet Union held the peace
Востоке Советский Союз держал пор мира
Russia can't even hold the Kursk
Россия не может удержать даже курскую
region But that's well if  in the Soviet Union
область Но это ну если в Советском Союзе
the boot stepped on it Although it is there now
сапог нав наступил Хоть она там сейчас
Russia in the Kursk region it simply
Россия в Курской области она просто Соин
drives out Soin knocks out little by little  look
выгоняет выбивает потихоньку смотри
let's do it this way Agree that a significant
давайте так Согласитесь что значительная
part of the Kursk region is not under the control of
часть Курской области не под контролем
Russia well what significant part on the
России ну какая значительная часть на
outskirts of the Kursk region some
окраинах Курской области некоторые
populated areas four districts four
населённые пун четыре района четыре
districts of the Kursk region are occupied by the
района Курской области заняты
armed forces of Ukraine Yeah what's
вооружёнными силами Украины Угу
the question If Naga had stepped on the Soviet Union even
че вопрос Если бы на Советский Союз хоть
1 centimeter
на 1 сантиметр ступила Нага солдата
another soldier  states what would the
другого государства что бы сделал
Soviet Union do Even under
Советский Союз Даже при
Gorbachev everything would have been done here and Vova
горбачёве всё бы сделал вот а Вовка
Putin Yes based on the film Kortik
Путин Да основанный на фильме Кортик
Yes
Да
now they talk about the brown lines the
теперь рассказывают про коричневые лини
new brown line but no one is afraid of it anymore
новая коричневая линия но его никто уже
everything is stupid the Americans gave us
не боится всё тупо американцы дали у нас
just here in Belgium yes the first month
просто вот в Бельгии да первый месяц
they were afraid  that Russia, in short, will strike with nuclear
боялись что Россия короче ударит ядерным
weapons and in short, that's why no one
оружием и короче поэтому никто не
interfered now everyone understands after the
вмешивался сейчас уже все понимают после
Crimean Bridge after
Крымского моста после
Belgorod and after the Kursk region after the
Белгорода да после Курской области после
Americans stupidly gave permission to
того что американцы дали тупо разрешение
strike with their missiles on
бить своими ракетами по территории
Russian territory and they said it directly in the Pentagon
России и прямо это сказали в пентагоне
they said to
сказали
strike today today they struck
бить сегодня сегодня ударили по
Rostov region pong my Rostov
Ростовской области понгу моя Ростовская
region tank city
область танк город
Chekhova separate person Joe Well which
Чехова отдельный человек Джо Ну которого
forgot Take the pills again it doesn't matter
забыл Принять таблетки ещё раз неважно
forgot or didn't forget  America is hitting
забыл или не забыл Америка бьёт своими
my native Rostov
ракетами по моей родной Ростовской
region with its missiles I have two Chust
области Я у меня двоя Чуст
Yes I saw some mu guy died there
Да я видел там какой-то му мужик умер
like in Tagonrog from Well and what are the victims of
типа в тагонрог из Ну и что вот жертвы
war you know Since Sanya Prokhorov Well
войны понимаешь Так как Саня Прохоров Ну
like there was he who this guy in short the Armed Forces are the
типа есть он был кому этот мужик короче
main  they banged Taganrog I don't like
ВС главно бахнули по таганрогу я не люб
these Taganskys In short we hit one guy with
этих таганских Короче мы одного мужика
nine missiles
девятью ракетами
this is what one civilian died
это го что один Гражданский погиб
how many missiles do you need to 140
сколько вам понадобится ракет чтобы 140
ml Russians
мл русских
this is l multiply by de missiles look what
это л умножьте на де ракет смотри каких
140 million Who needs you for example So you
140 млн Кому ты например нужен Так тебе
look bang bang they will put on the Kremlin
смотри бахну бахну по Кремлю поставят
you have a new management like Yeltsin
тебе новое руководство как Ельцина
was put in after Gorbachev yes as a
поставили после Горбачёва да В
result of losing the cold war yes
результате проигрыша в холодной войне Да
and you will continue to be an
и ты будешь дальше
architect 8000 rubles you will continue to
архитектором 8000 руб будешь дальше
work as an architect who
работать архитектором кому ты
needs you spends a rocket on you are you
нужен на тебя ракету тратит Ты что
kidding me
прикалываешься
you will never earn enough in your life for a microchip from a
Ты в жизни не заработаешь на микрочип от
rocket so first they  we still
ракеты так это сначала они ещё
have to defeat us
должны победить нас
for them to come here so you already
это чтобы они сюда пришли так вас уже
already won in Kursk region Yes already in
победили уже в Курской области Да уже в
Kursk region obla This is all of Russia so
Курской области обла Это вся Россия так
look The point is that you have
смотри Суть в том что вы ничего не
done nothing Euro NATO not America And
сделали евро НАТО не Америки А
we we
мы мы
you simply and that's all And what will you do And what will
вас просто и всё И что вы сделаете А что
you do the flowerpot will water itself you
ты сделаешь вазон польёт у себя ковёр вы
pulled the carpet  tiger by the tail 8 years of the
дёргали тигра за хвост 8 лет
tiger Yes, they pulled the tiger by the tail
тигра Да тигра дёргали за хвост тигра
laughing and laughing
смея и смеялись
hahaha come on come on It
хахаха давай давай
seems to me that you are exaggerating a little this is
Мне кажется вы немножко преувеличить это
not a
не
tiger this is our
тигр это наше
patience Vova he is a loyal person
терпение Вовка он лояльный человек
loyal he is with a cold mind ra he is a
лояльный он такой с холодным умом ра он
calculating
расчётливый
fight be afraid of the wrath of a patient person
бой бойся гнева терпеливого человека
explain [ __ ]
обясни сри
yesterday  yesterday in Moscow with the help of a scooter of a
вчера вчера в Москве с помою самоката
Russian general of a man who
российского генерала человека который
was part of the General Staff how did Vova react
входил в генштаб как отреагировал Вовка
that you underestimate your
в том что вы недооцениваете своего
enemy how did Vova react that
противника как Вовка отреагировал что
they killed a Russian General in the center of
грохнули российского Генерала в центре
Moscow and I haven't seen the latest news
Москвы а я новости последние не
he
видел он так
understands with regret
понимаю сожалением
regret to react he reacted
сожалением отреагировать он отреагировал
with regret this  a person with a cold mind
с сожалением это человек с холодным умом
he is not well what for example  there the hazelnut
он не ну что например там орешник
launched on the bank on Washington how do you
запустил по банковой по вашингтону как
not understand Putin you still have not
не понимаете Путина вы до сих пор его не
studied him he does not show his
изучили он не показывает свои
emotions This is a man with a cold
эмоции Это человек с холодным
mind but this does not mean that he is there it
умом но это не значит что он там это вам
seems to you from the outside not he is not he has
так со стороны кажется не он не у него
wealth an
богатство
architect who in  Russia works for
архитектор который в России работает за
rubles and Putin is an
руб а Путин
architect for how much should he work
архитектор за сколько он должен работать
for
за
how much is a sucker
сколь терпила
this is a
это прит
parable they pay money in Ukraine and at the
вро платят деньги на Украине и он при
same time he is for this guy you work as an
этом за этот чувак ты работаешь
architect 80,000 so this is your
архитектором 80.000 так это твоя
desired salary and you say that
желаемая зарплата и ты говоришь что
Putin Putin did not
Путин Путин не
terminate
тер
Minimal Putin  not how much you well How much do
Минимал Путин не сколько ты ну Сколько
you earn Look I earn
ты зарабатываешь Смотри Я зарабатываю
7,000
7.000
euros I work in an office well How much do you
евро в конторе работаю ну Сколько ты
earn
зарабатываешь
2 s not how much my salary is 25 cm I
2 с не сколько зарплата у меня 25 см я
understand 25 cm from the carpet to this to the
понял 25 см от ковра до этого до
closet
шкафа
And you can earn 7,000 Of course if
А 7.000 можно зарабатывать Конечно если
you engage in Russo propaganda on the salary of
заниматься Русо пропагандой на заплате
the State Department  can you watch this I would of course be
госдепа можно это смотрите Я конечно был
glad I would be glad if EPL
рад я бы рад был если мне епл
does it for me from the heart But if the guest wants Yes
делаю от души Но если гостеп захочет Да
and will send me payment for
и пришлёт мне оплату за
ru I will be glad honestly will not refuse if
ру Я буду рад честно не откажусь если
if somewhere the state department hears me and decides to
если где-то госдеп меня услышит и решит
throw me some type of payment I
мне подкинуть какого-то типа оплаты я
only accept for from year I
только за от годе по принимаю Я ничего
don't see anything bad here and what And what if the state department
не вижу плохого тут и что А что госдеп
doesn't send anything  no no I it hurts
не присылает ничего нет нет я меня болит
me it hurts for my homeland yes I grew up
меня за мою родину болит да Я вырос
in Russia after all I haven't lived there for 18 years
всё-таки в России я 18 лет не живу там
yes but my parents live there if my
да но там мои родители живут если у меня
mother worked as a nurse Yes in the
мама проработала медсестрой Да в
Rostov hospital all her life and gets
Ростовской больнице всю жизнь и получает
a salary of 18,000 rubles Oh not a salary  And
18.000 руб зарплату Ой не зарплату А
a pension of 180 dollars is a disgrace for Russia,
пенсию 180 долларов это позор для России
which has oil, gas, gold,
которой есть нефть газ золото
diamonds, it's a
алмазы позор это
disgrace, it's a disgrace. And what about in Belgium, everyone gets
позор А что там в Бельгии все получают
7,000 euros. Yes, per month. Well,
7.000 евро Да в месяц Да ну как бы 180
no one gets 180 euros. No
евро не получает
one. The minimum
никто никто Да никто никто минималка
[music] is
[музыка]
1,500, well, the main thing is to name it.  a bigger number
1500 ну главное назвать цифру побольше
No, don't take it Check And how much is
Да не возьми Проверь А сколько в России
the minimum in Russia 19,000 rubles now 190 dollars
минималка 19.000 руб сейчас 190 долларов
I don't know how much  in Russia Nika Who
Я не знаю сколько в России Ника Кто как
lives how Everyone lives differently
живёт Все живут по-разному
You
у тебя жена
have a wife I don't Of course why well Was Was there
есть меня нет Конечно зачем ну Была Был
was
была
a girl there was no wife I didn't want How
девушка жены не было я не хотел Сколько
old are you
лет
41 I'm 43 we are
41 мне 43 мы
lower deputy
пониже зам
conversation I am against a
разговор я против того чтобы
man
мужчина
allowing him to be used now very much
позволял использовать его сейчас очень
feminism is very developed, matriarchy is
сильно развит феминизм матриархат
just off the charts and we need to
зашкаливает просто и нам надо
return to old traditions and
возвращаться к прежним традициям и
establish our own rules and not follow
устанавливать свои порядки а не идти на
what is written in this
поводу того что там прописано в этом
damn code, it's high time to change it,
долбаного кодексе его давно пора менять
sign up for it.
подписываться Под таким семейным
This is not allowed under such a family code under any circumstances,
кодексом это нельзя ни в коем случае
write to my Telegram directly  now axis VN
пись на мий Telegram прям зараз ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
with us through the SRG ORV in your ban and very
нас через срг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos are not shown to people at times do not
багато видео не показуе людям вчасно не
show information about streams so
показуе информация про стримы тому для
that we Mali operational links
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
are written right now and Popik there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegram okrim video more  tezh  interesting and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we will oblige you with
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
constant operational links
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that will show you about this
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
subscribe and
подпишись а